# Elena Gutiérrez Viedma



Age24 (November 10, 1993)Place of birthMadrid, SpainNationalitySpanishEmailelena.gutierrez@imdea.org

Website http://software.imdea.org/~elena.gutierrez/

**Address** IMDEA Software Institute

Office 342

Campus de Montegancedo s/n 28223 - Pozuelo de Alarcón

Madrid, Spain

## **About Me**

I am a second-year PhD. student at the IMDEA Software Institute in Madrid, under the supervision of Prof. Pierre Ganty. Before, I studied a Double Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science at Universidad Autónoma de Madrid. During my summer breaks, I have enjoyed three research internships at IMDEA Software working with Ganty on formal verification of programs using Horn clauses.

Now, my research interests are mainly focused in the theory of formal languages and automata and its applications to software verification. I am also interested in Horn clause verification, and logic and functional programming.

## **Research Experience**

**Sept. 2016 - present** IMDEA Software Institute

PhD. in Software, Systems and Computing supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Sept. 2015 - Feb. 2016 IMDEA Software Institute

Degree Thesis supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

2013 - 2015 IMDEA Software Institute

Three-month research summer internships

### Education

2011-2016 Double Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid | Average Grade (out of 10) - 8.21

### **Publications**

**2017** Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata

P. Ganty and E. Gutiérrez. FCT 2017

**2018** The Parikh Property for Weighted Context-Free Grammars

P. Ganty and E. Gutiérrez. FSTTCS 2018

# **Bachelor's Project**

**2016** Linearisation of Index Bounded Sets of Horn Clauses.

Supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

This thesis presents a Prolog algorithm that transforms non-linear logic programs into linear

preserving their meaning Grade (out of 10) - 10

## Schools/Seminars Attended

- Microsoft Research PhD. Summer School. 4–8, July, 2016. Cambridge, UK.
- ullet 2nd School on Formal Verification by The Hebrew University. 17–21, December, 2017. Jerusalem, Israel.

## **Conference/Public Talks**

March, 2017 Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata
S3, Seminar Series at Imdea Software Institute. March 7<sup>th</sup>, 2017

Sept., 2017 Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata
Presentation at FCT 2017 in Bordeaux, France. September 11<sup>th</sup>, 2017

April, 2018 Weighted Context-Free Grammars: Does Parikh's Theorem still hold?
S3, Seminar Series at Imdea Software Institute. April 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2018

Sept., 2018 The Parikh Property for Weighted Context-Free Grammars
Formal Methods and Verification Seminar at the Université Libre de Bruxelles. September 26<sup>th</sup>, 2018

## Languages

Spanish Native

**English** Fluent TOEFL iBT (Feb. 2016). Total (out of 120): 104

French Basic

# **Programing Languages**

• Prolog, Haskell, C, Python, ŁTĘX

#### Grants

2017-2021 Predoctoral Contract for PhD. Training Grant (FPI)

Provided by the Spanish Ministry of Economy, Industry and Competitiveness

### **Additional Information**

**Teaching Experience** Support classes for students at secondary education

Mathematics, English, Physics and Chemistry

Volunteer work International exchange organization AFS

Coordination of exchange activities for foreign students in Spain

Soñar Despierto Foundation

Support classes for students coming from marginalized backgrounds